Now I think enough and a lot are very interesting.
现在我想够了，很多很有趣。
We could say a lot or lots.
我们可以说很多或很多。
Pretty much the same thing.
几乎是一样的。
Lots lots of very interesting because they can be used both with countable and uncountable nouns.
很多非常有趣，因为它们可以与可数名词和不可数名词一起使用。
So if you're ever wondering well I want to say a huge amount but I don't know which word to use you
所以如果你想知道我想说很多但我不知道该用哪个词
should use a lot.
应该用很多。
You should use lots if you want to say well this is the right amount.
如果你想说这是正确的数量，你应该使用很多。
You should say enough.
你应该说够了。
And it doesn't usually matter if it's countable or uncountable.
它是可数还是不可数通常并不重要。
They can be used with both.
它们可以与两者一起使用。
Let's look at some examples.
让我们看一些例子。
OK.
好的。
Beer is beer countable or uncountable.
啤酒是可数或不可数的啤酒。
Well sometimes it's countable.
嗯，有时它是可数的。
Usually beer is uncountable.
通常啤酒是不可数的。
OK.
好的。
It's uncountable you know.
你知道的数不胜数。
And so if I say there's there's enough beer for everyone.
因此，如果我说每个人都有足够的啤酒。
Help yourself.
帮助自己。
It's enough beer for everyone.
这对每个人来说都足够了。
Help yourself take as much as you want.
帮助自己尽可能多地服用。
So enough means that it satisfies the need.
所以足够意味着它满足了需求。
There's a need here and whatever amount this is satisfies that need.
这里有一个需求，无论数量多少都可以满足这一需求。
It's the right amount for that need.
这是满足这种需求的合适数量。
OK.
好的。
So there's enough beer this is for an uncountable noun beer.
所以有足够的啤酒这是不可数名词啤酒。
And we can do the same thing if we're talking about food like cat food which is also uncountable but
如果我们谈论像猫粮这样的食物，我们也可以做同样的事情，这也是不可数的，但
we can use not not enough if we want to say that the requirement is this much and there is too little
如果我们想说需求这么多，那么我们可以使用不够不够
for that.
为了那个原因。
We've we've learned little.
我们学到的很少。
Right.
正确的。
So there's too little.
所以太少了。
There should be more.
应该有更多。
So if if there isn't.
所以如果没有的话。
Which means is not enough cat food.
这意味着没有足够的猫粮。
Go buy more.
去买更多。
If there isn't enough cat food go buy more.
如果没有足够的猫粮去买更多。
OK.
好的。
This is a very very common way to express that we need to get something.
这是一种非常常见的表达方式，即我们需要得到一些东西。
We need to get something.
我们需要得到一些东西。
There isn't enough.
还不够。
You didn't get enough.
你没有得到足够的。
Please go buy more.
请多买点。
You didn't get enough cat food.
你没有得到足够的猫粮。
Can you please buy some more.
你能再买一些吗？
Or if we wanted to say something countable we could say you didn't buy enough cups you didn't buy enough
或者，如果我们想说一些可数的话，我们可以说你买的杯子不够多，你买的不够多
cups countable please go buy more please go buy more.
可数杯请多买多买。
All right.
好的。
So again countable or uncountable.
所以又是可数的或不可数的。
They work for both.
他们为两者工作。
Do you know Sesame Street that TV show for kids.
你知道芝麻街那个儿童电视节目吗？
There's a blue monster on there.
那里有一个蓝色怪物。
His name is Cookie Monster.
他的名字是饼干怪兽。
He loves cookies.
他喜欢饼干。
I love Cookie Monster cookies are accountable.
我爱 Cookie Monster 饼干是负责任的。
OK so Cookie Monster on num num num num cookie monster gets very angry if he doesn't get enough cookies
好的，所以 num num num cookie Monster 上的 Cookie Monster 如果没有得到足够的饼干会非常生气
if you watch Cookie Monster on Sesame Street you will see he gets very unhappy if he does not get enough
如果你在芝麻街上看饼干怪兽，你会发现如果他没有得到足够的东西，他会很不开心
cookies.
饼干。
Very angry.
很生气。
OK.
好的。
A lot.
很多。
Lots also for countable and uncountable very very useful.
很多也对可数和不可数非常有用。
And it's basically similar to many but many is for countable things.
它与许多基本相似，但许多是用于可数事物。
So it's a large amount of something a large amount of something.
所以它是大量的东西大量的东西。
It's the opposite of saying for example little it's the opposite of saying Phew.
例如，这与说“小”相反，与“唷”相反。
Phew is a small amount.
呸是少量。
Little is a small amount.
少量是少量。
OK.
好的。
It's the opposite.
恰恰相反。
Here we go.
开始了。
I've got I've got lots of good ideas.
我有我有很多好主意。
I've got lots of good ideas ideas countable or uncountable.
我有很多可数或不可数的好主意。
It is countable one idea two ideas three ideas countable countable.
它是可数一念二念三念可数可数。
There's a lot more snow coming tomorrow.
明天还要下很多雪。
So a lot more snow coming tomorrow.
所以明天会有更多的雪。
OK snow countable or uncountable uncountable cannot count snow.
OK snow 可数或不可数不可数不可数雪。
You can say snow flake teeny teeny tiny little thing a snow flake AFL AK e but usually snow is uncountable.
你可以说 snow flake teeny teeny tiny little thing a snow flake AFL AK e 但通常雪是不可数的。
Let's look at a couple more examples of this one.
让我们再看几个例子。
Oh by the way can we say there's lots more snow.
哦，顺便说一句，我们可以说还有更多的雪。
Is that the same.
是不是一样。
Yes it's the same.
是的，它是一样的。
It's exactly the same.
完全一样。
There's a lot more there's lots more.
还有很多还有很多。
Those are the same.
那些是一样的。
You're you're asking a lot of questions today.
你今天问了很多问题。
That's great.
那太棒了。
OK.
好的。
One more example one more example.
再举一例再举一例。
A lot of people don't like classical music people countable or uncountable here countable.
很多人不喜欢古典音乐人可数或不可数这里可数。
One person two people three people countable a lot of people don't like classical music for some reason
一个人 两个人 三人 可数很多人出于某种原因不喜欢古典音乐
I like it.
我喜欢。
I used to remember lots of my dreams but now I don't.
我曾经记得很多我的梦想，但现在我不记得了。
OK.
好的。
Dreams countable or uncountable countable wondering to dreams countable.
梦可数或不可数可数想知道梦可数。
OK so these two both really useful to express things that are both countable and uncountable.
好的，所以这两个对于表达可数和不可数的东西都非常有用。
OK.
好的。
Very useful.
很有用。